

Thirunavukkarasu Muthusamy

Thiru has accumulated significant programming experience in a variety of areas of we development, including back-end (Java and Node.IS) and front-end (HTML, CSS, JavaScript/Ext.IS/Anguler.IS) He has built many successful web apps that operate on pletforms, including lonic and Cordove.

Digitally offload at: http://youtube.com/IndustryVertical (de offload at: http://github.com/Thirunavukkaras Thoughts offload at: http://thirunavukkarasu.com Apache Web Server Application Server Oracle DB Hu

JavaScript HTML5 CSS Java GitHub

PORTFOLIO The Nielsen Company - Locations
Javascript/ExtJS, Java, Pitney Spectrum
Server, Hudson CI Server, Oracle App
Server, Apache Web Server, Bash Shell,
HTML5, CSS, SASS, SQL

The Nielsen Company - Product and ands
vascript/ExtJS, Java, Terracotta Cac
rver, Jenkins Cl Server, Oracle App
rver, Apache Web Server

Web server Admin, 3 years Database Admin, 1 year Build Engineer, 3 years

Web Developer and Platform Engineer
The Nielsen Company - Product and Brands

decoupling the various modules Attended the training on Sencha ExtJS 6 Framework

EXPERIENCE

App server Admin, 3 ye

Linux/Bash Scripting, 3) HTML/CSS, 3 years JavaScript, 3 years ExtJS, 2 years AngularJS, 1 year Java, 2 years

PREFERRED ENVIRONMENT

Linux, Eclipse, Sublime Text, Git

Started the proposal of migrating the Tibco GI based application to Sencha Excls from scratch Collaborated with people from Sencha company, for building the base layout and UI componer Collaborated with Sencha and Nielsen Architects to have proper packaging structure, event handling and

Senior Web Developer and Platform Engineer

The Nielsen Company - Locations

Maintaining consistency code maintenance as the codebase is common across PnB and Location

Collaborated with Architects on developing the HLD for Locations Stores and Accounts modules

Enforcing developers to keep on revisting the code and explaining the importance following common

Collaborated with existing Tibco GI developers to understand from existing component
 Training and mentoring the Front-end developers

Conducting Quiz programs and arranging for pause-a

Installing and Configuring Cache server/clusters

 Attended the training on Sentine EXUS 6 Framework
 Started building the reusable Grid, OuerBuilder, Enumerations and Form component
 Automating the ExtJS build process for non-production and production environments Code revisit, review and enforcing associates to follow the JavaScript coding standards Making sure that whether all the 20 developers following the best pra
 Developing JAX-RS RESTful webservices for various modules Installing and Configuring Application servers/clusters Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java, SQL, Bash, Hudson, Weblogic

THE MOST AMAZING...

THE MUST ARRACTION.

Software I've ever created is a Monitoring Dashboard suite that determines the pletform assets heat in different levels, that includes Application level, JVM level, Machine level and Client/Server connectivity level. And it is built on top of AngularJS, fwiter Bootstrep, D3JS, Java, NodeJS, Bash and PhantomJS

Kelambak

(49A)

2012 - 2016

2012 - 2016

PHILOSOPHY Be the fear, become the fear, melt in the fear and then blow a flying kiss to your fear!

EMPLOYMENT

PROJECTS FOR FUN

EDUCATION

SKILLS

2011

2007 - 2011

Installing and Configuring Spectrum server
Developing end-to-end deployment flow using Ant and Shell scripts Technologies: Java and JavaScript Siruseri Runners - A Marathon Website Developed using AngularJS, NodeJS, Heroku and Twitter Bootstra Demo: http://siruseri-runners.herokuapp.com Sedikor - A Business Website Developed using AngularJS and Twitter Bootstrap Demo: http://thirunavukkarasu.github.io/Sedikor/ Anju Weds Srini - A Wedding Website Developed using JQuery, UnderscoreJS, PHP and Twitter Bootstrap
Demo: http://thirunavukkarasu.github.io/Wedding-Website/ Observer - A Monitoring Dasboard Developed using HighCharts, JQuery and Twitter Bootstrap Demo: http://thirunavukkarasu.github.io/HighCharts-Demo/ Languages
HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, ECMAScript, SCSS, SASS, Java, NodeJS, Bash, XML/JSO erJS, DalekJS, D3JS, C3JS, Underscore.js, JQuery, Twillo, Quartz, Ehcach aradigms nile Software Development, Test-driven Development (TDD)

Tools GitHub, Git, Subl

Training in Redhat Linux Server Administration Rajalakshmi Engineering College - Anna University - Chennai

Bachelor's degree in Information Technology Rajalakshmi Engineering College - Anna University - Chennai

Platforms Windows, Redhat Linux, OS X, Ghost Storage Oracle DB, Mongo DB, MySQL

Misc Fedora/Ubuntu Linux,Oracle Weblogic, Apache Web

Training in Senca ExtJS 6 JavaScript Framework Tata Consultancy Services - Chennai

Certification in Application Server Administration Oracle Weblogic Java EE App server - Chennal